<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Museum Tour</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string-array name="short_exhibit_names">
        <item >Scratch</item>
        <item >Room 10-250</item>
        <item >UROP</item>
        <item >Independent Activities Period</item>
        <item >2.70/2.007 MIT\'s Most Famous Class</item>
        <item >Daedalus Human-Powered Flight Team</item>
        <item >Google App Inventor</item>
        <item >GNU Manifesto</item>
        <item >MIT Project Athena</item>
        <item >Theseus Maze</item>
        <item >Slide Rules</item>
        <item >Differential Analyzer</item>
        <item >Ray and Maria Stata Center</item>
        <item >Parker\'s Plasma Sculptures</item>
        <item >Digital Holography</item>
        <item >MIT Glass Lab</item>
        <item >LeWitt\'s Bars of Color within Squares</item>
        <item >Calder\'s La Grande Voile</item>
        <item >Artificial "Skin"</item>
        <item >H.M.\'s Brain</item>
        <item >PowerFoot One Prosthetic Foot</item>
        <item >Boston Arm</item>
        <item >"Minksy Arm"</item>
        <item >Stair-Climbing Wheelchair</item>
        <item >Boston\s Central Artery/Tunnel Plan</item>
        <item >Boston Chinatown Master Plan</item>
        <item >Perceptual Form of the City</item>
        <item >Charles River as Research Lab</item>
        <item >Boston Wind Tunnel Studies</item>
        <item >Weather Radar Research</item>
        <item >OpenCourseWare</item>
        <item >Compton Lecture Series</item>
        <item >MIT Science Reporter</item>
        <item >MIT Press\' Most Influential Works</item>
        <item >MIT\'s World\'s Fair Photographic Albums</item>
        <item >MIT\'s Mid-Century Convocation</item>
        <item >MIT $100K Competition</item>
        <item >One Laptop per Child</item>
        <item >SR-4 Strain Gauge</item>
        <item >MIT Sloan Fellows</item>
        <item >Perfect Cup of Coffee Research</item>
        <item >MIT\'s First Patent Policy</item>
        <item >Whitehead Human Genome Project</item>
        <item >Edgerton\'s High-Speed Pictures</item>
        <item >Van de Graaff Generators</item>
        <item >Feynman Diagrams</item>
        <item >Chomsky\'s Elements of Linguistic Structure</item>
        <item >MIT\'s First Wind-Tunnel</item>
        <item >CityCar Electric Vehicle</item>
        <item >Protein Folding</item>
        <item >Cancer Research</item>
        <item >MIT Nuclear Research Reactor</item>
        <item >Copenhagen Wheel</item>
        <item >Presidential Science Advisors</item>
        <item >"IHTFP"</item>
        <item >MIT\'s Living Groups</item>
        <item >Baker House Piano Drop</item>
        <item >Hacking - The Smoot</item>
        <item >MIT Class of 2011 Brass Rat</item>
        <item >MIT\'s Great Dome</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="exhibit_names">
        <item >Scratch, Mitchel Resnick, MIT Media Laboratory Lifelong Kindergarten Group, 2007</item>
        <item >Original Seats from Room 10-250, MIT\'s Most Famous Lecture Hall, 1916–1977</item>
        <item >Undergraduate Research Opportunities Program (UROP), 1969—Present</item>
        <item >IAP’s Most Famous Class: “How to Gamble If You Will” (Training Grounds for the MIT Blackjack Team), 1979</item>
        <item >2.70/2.007 MIT\'s Most Famous Class, 1970–Present</item>
        <item >Daedalus 87, Daedalus Human-Powered Flight Team, 1985–1988</item>
        <item >Google App Inventor, Hal Abelson, 2010</item>
        <item >GNU Manifesto, Richard Stallman, 1985</item>
    	<item >MIT Project Athena, 1983–1991</item>
    	<item >Theseus Maze, Claude Shannon, 1952</item>
    	<item >Slide Rules, Classroom Demonstration Slide Rule, Pickett N500-ES, Pickett and Eckel Inc., c. 1964</item>
    	<item >Differential Analyzer, Vannevar Bush, 1931</item>
    	<item >Ray and Maria Stata Center, Frank Gehry, 2004</item>
    	<item >Plasma Sculptures, William Parker, 1972</item>
    	<item >Digital Holography, Stephen Benton, Spatial Imaging Group, MIT Media Laboratory, and Brigham and Women’s Hospital, 1985</item>
    	<item >MIT Glass Lab, Four Pieces, 1972–Present</item>
    	<item >Bars of Color within Squares, Sol Lewitt, 2007</item>
    	<item >La Grande Voile, Alexander Calder, 1966</item>
    	<item >Artificial "Skin", Ioannis Yannas, 1970—Present</item>
    	<item >Sections, H.M.’s Brain, Suzanne Corkin, 1953–Present</item>
    	<item >PowerFoot One Prosthetic Foot, Hugh Herr, 2007</item>
    	<item >Boston Arm (Elbow) Prototypes, Robert Mann, 1966–1973</item>
    	<item >“Minsky Arm,” Marvin Minsky, 1967–1973</item>
    	<item >Stair-Climbing Wheelchair, Ernesto Blanco, 1962</item>
    	<item >Boston’s Central Artery/Tunnel Plan, Frederick Salvucci, 1970s</item>
    	<item >Boston Chinatown Master Plan, Tunney Lee, 2010</item>
    	<item >Maps for the Perceptual Form of the City Study, Architecture and Planning Graduate Students, 1954, 1960</item>
    	<item >Charles River, Side Scan Sonar Towfish, Martin Klein and Klein Associates, Inc., 1970</item>
    	<item >Boston Wind Tunnel Models, Frank Durgin and Wright Brothers Wind Tunnel, 1970s</item>
    	<item >Weather Radar Research, Postcards, Klystron, Spiros Geotis, 1960–1963</item>
    	<item >OpenCourseWare, 2000—Present, “Physics Works,” Conservation of Mechanical Energy Promotional Video for MIT 8.001 course, Walter Lewin, 2007</item>
    	<item >Karl Taylor Compton Lecture Series, Paul A. Samuelson and Milton Friedman, 1969</item>
    	<item >MIT Science Reporter, MIT and WGBH Boston, 1950s–1960s</item>
    	<item >MIT Press’ Most Influential Publications, 1926–Present</item>
    	<item >MIT’s World’s Fair Photographic Albums, 1893–1904</item>
    	<item >MIT’s Mid-Century Convocation, Winston Churchill, 1949</item>
    	<item >MIT $100K Entrepreneurship Competition, 2010 Winner’s Check and Trophy, 1989–Present</item>
    	<item >One Laptop per Child XO Laptop, Nicholas Negroponte, 2002</item>
    	<item >Invention of the Strain Gauge, Arthur Ruge, 1938</item>
    	<item >MIT Sloan Fellows, 1938–Present</item>
    	<item >Perfect Cup of Coffee Research, Samuel Cate Prescott, 1930s</item>
    	<item >MIT\'s first patent policy, 1932</item>
    	<item >Whitehead Institute Human Genome Project, Eric Lander, 1986–2004</item>
    	<item >High-Speed Motion Pictures, Harold E. Edgerton, 1936, 1965</item>
    	<item >Electrostatic Generators, Robert Van de Graaff, 1931</item>
    	<item >Feynman Diagrams, Richard Feynman, 1949</item>
    	<item >Elements of Linguistic Structure, Noam Chomsky, 1955</item>
    	<item >Wind Tunnel Balance and Test Model, MIT Aeronautics Department, 1913</item>
    	<item >CityCar Electric Vehicle, Smart Cities Group, MIT Media Laboratory, 2006–Present</item>
    	<item >Protein Folding, Susan Lindquist, 1980s–Present</item>
    	<item >Cancer Research, Salvador Luria, 1960s</item>
    	<item >MITR II, MIT Laboratory for Nuclear Science, 1958–Present</item>
    	<item >Copenhagen Wheel, MIT SENSEable Cities Laboratory, 2011</item>
    	<item >Presidential Science Advisors, James Killian, and President Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1958</item>
    	<item >“IHTFP”</item>
    	<item >MIT\'s Greek Life, Chair from MIT’s Oldest Fraternity, Sigma Chi, 1882; Banner from MIT\'s Oldest Sorority, Alpha Kappa Alpha, 1977</item>
    	<item >Baker House Piano Drop, 2010</item>
    	<item >Hacking – The Smoot, Smoot Bar, Oliver Smoot and the Brothers of Lambda Chi, 1958 and 2008</item>
    	<item >Brass Rat, MIT Class of 2011 Ring, 2011</item>
    	<item >MIT\'s Great Dome, 1916</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="exhibit_text">
        <item >\t Early childhood education and the most advanced artificial intelligence have more in common than you might think—one school of thought on teaching machines how to learn focuses on figuring out how children learn and then mimicking that process. Educational robotics and software developed at CSAIL, the Media Lab, and other MIT departments and centers have helped children to learn about computers and computers to learn about the world. The long history of these kinds of MIT projects includes LOGO turtles, Lego-LOGO, Lego Mindstorms, programmable Crickets, and One Laptop per Child. Scratch is a recent project that allows users to combine new and preexisting sounds, graphics, and program pieces with the same freedom and creativity that they might use to combine vinyl record samples into a new piece of music. Sit down and learn how the program works!</item>
        <item >\t The laboratory, the library, and the lecture hall are the quintessential spaces of any university campus. Directly above you is MIT’s most significant space, known simply as Room 10-250. Nobel Prize winners and MIT presidents have been introduced to the world in this room. World-renowned figures have lectured here. Students lucky enough to be in Professor Donald Sadoway’s oversubscribed materials science course (3.091) have squeezed into this hall three times a week. For nearly a century, thousands of students have listened to lectures, attended demonstrations, watched movies, and enjoyed student group performances here. They have been enthralled, engaged, and, on a few occasions, put to sleep in this lecture hall. Today, through online programs such as MIT Video, TechTV, and OpenCourseWare, you can experience some of the myriad offerings in this space even if you are far from Cambridge.</item>
        <item >\t “MIT is deeply committed to the premise that undergraduates should inhabit a very special world—that of a moral and intellectual universe with certain fixed stars, but also with wide spaces in between where students can find room to wander and to make their own paths.”  – Margaret McVicar, founder of UROP
		\n \t Jennifer Wiseman was one of these students. Attending the MIT Astronomy Field Camp at Lowell Observatory in January 1987, she discovered a comet while scrutinizing these glass plate negatives. The initial observation led to a spring UROP project that became her undergraduate thesis and launched her career as an astronomer.
		\n \t Inspired by Edwin Land, inventor of instant photography, Physics Professor Margaret McVicar founded MIT’s Undergraduate Research Opportunities Program in 1969. During that first year, 20 students participated. Today, more than 85 percent of undergraduates participate in the program. MIT has spent well over $100 million on the UROP program—transforming the lives of students,  redefining the nature of research at MIT, and even inspiring the award-winning public television series, Design Squad.</item>
    	<item >\t From the earliest days of the Institute’s existence, MIT faculty recognized that extracurricular activities were vital to their students’ education. To that end, MIT has always encouraged as many projects as students could dream up. One of the most significant academic innovations at the Institute was the creation of the Independent Activities Period (IAP). Four weeks of unfettered exploration, experimentation, and education, IAP is held each January between the fall and spring semesters. Open to the entire MIT community, thousands of courses, lectures, seminars, and special events have been offered over the past 40 years, ranging from mystery hunts and poetry discussions to MATLab seminars and public-service projects. Some offerings have gained considerable public attention, including “Charm School,” the 6.270 robot competition, and an especially notorious seminar begun in 1979 that taught the rudiments of card counting. Fictionalized accounts of the MIT Blackjack Team—including two best-selling books and a feature motion picture—plus three television documentaries, multiple news accounts, and numerous commentaries have made “How to Gamble if You Will” IAP’s most famous course.</item>
    	<item >\t Prof. Woodie Flowers handed a syllabus to students enrolled in course 2.70, the Mechanical Engineering “Introduction to Design” class, with a simple but maddening challenge: “design and build a robotic system for putting a round peg in a square hole, while a competing system tries to put another peg into the same hole.” Students received a box of supplies—a variety of cardboard tubes, cords, two motors, sprockets, and rubber bands—and a series of lectures that introduced the fundamentals of design. The course is demanding, but students love it. Hundreds now pack the “final competition” cheering on friends, the most elegant contraption, or even the biggest failure. For four decades, this hands-on course has taught “gracious professionalism.” Recently renamed course 2.007 “Design and Manufacturing,” it has become one of MIT’s iconic classes, inspiring other engineering education programs at the Institute, such as the 6.270 class, and at other institutions, including the FIRST Robotics Competition for high school students.</item>
    	<item >\t In April 1988, a team of 40 MIT students, faculty, and alumni set a world record for human-powered flight. Piloted by Greek cycling champion Kanellos Kanellopoulos, Daedalus 88 flew 74 miles from Crete to Santorini in a re-creation of the mythological flight of the craft’s namesake. Under the leadership of graduate student John Langford, the project began three years earlier as a partnership between MIT and the Smithsonian Institution’s National Air and Space Museum. Following a successful feasibility study, the prototype aircraft Michelob Light Eagle was built and tested at Lincoln Laboratory’s Flight Test Facility and the NASA Dryden Flight Research Center. Pilots Lois McCallin and Glenn Tremml set four world records for human-powered flight in January 1987. Support from United Technologies and dozens of other corporations inspired the construction of the real aircraft—Daedalus 87 and Daedalus 88—as well as the trip to Greece the following year that would shatter those earlier records. The project’s success made MIT front-page news around the globe. This major cultural endeavor not only involved active collaboration between two nations, but also spurred the formation of a new company, engineering research, and major curriculum reform in aerospace engineering at MIT and beyond.</item>
    	<item >\t Today, 45 million people in the United States are using a smartphone, and the number is growing rapidly. These devices not only have put the Internet in our pockets, but also have altered our ideas of computers as static machines. One of the most important areas of research at MIT concerns ubiquitous computing. During a sabbatical year at Google, professor Hal Abelson invented software that would enable everyone to program an “App” for their phones. Google App Inventor is brand-new, but it represents a key philosophy espoused by Abelson: “If your phone is going to be an influential force in your life, then you should be able to shape it to suit your needs whether or not you have a degree in computer science or electrical engineering.” The video and simulation here provide a good idea of the future envisioned by Abelson.</item>
    	<item >\t Why I Must Write GNU
		\n \t I consider that the golden rule requires that if I like a program I must share it with other people who like it. Software sellers want to divide the users and conquer them, making each user agree not to share with others. I refuse to break solidarity with other users in this way. I cannot in good conscience sign a nondisclosure agreement or a software license agreement. For years I worked within the Artificial Intelligence Lab to resist such tendencies and other inhospitalities, but eventually they had gone too far: I could not remain in an institution where such things are done for me against my will.
		\n \t So that I can continue to use computers without dishonor, I have decided to put together a sufficient body of free software so that I will be able to get along without any software that is not free. I have resigned from the AI lab to deny MIT any legal excuse to prevent me from giving GNU away.
		\n \t Richard Stallman, from the GNU Manifesto, 1985
		\n \t Stallman’s radical ideals launched the “free software” movement and profoundly shaped contemporary public understanding of moral and legal rights regarding the development and use of computer software.</item>
    	<item >\t Project Athena was an eight-year (1983–1991), $100 million collaborative project involving MIT, IBM, and Digital Equipment Corporation (DEC) to integrate computers into the university curriculum at MIT and beyond. The project stimulated many influential applications, such as Instant Messaging, Active Directory, and the X Window System. But the real goal was to make very powerful software available for students, faculty, and staff to do almost anything—from sending email and writing papers to analyzing data and creating new applications. Getting an Athena account is one of the first things all new members of the MIT community do when they arrive. Though powerful wireless networks provide near-universal Wi-Fi access across campus, students still love using the Athena Clusters.</item>
    	<item >\t Harvard professor and expert on multiple intelligences Howard Gardner said Claude Shannon’s MIT master’s thesis was “possibly the most important, and also the most famous, master’s thesis of the century.” If you’ve used the word “bit” (for binary digit), then you have an idea of what he meant. More important, Claude Shannon’s early ideas proved key to the redesign of the telephone system and the development of the modern computer. During WWII, he met the famous British mathematician Alan Turing. That exchange resulted in Shannon’s pioneering analysis of cryptography systems. (A declassified version of his original 1945 memo was published in 1949.) Most notably, Shannon’s 1948 paper, A Mathematical Theory of Communication, was hailed as “the Magna Carta of the information age.”
		\n \t This digital pioneer had another extremely imaginative and playful side. Shannon loved to build mechanical toys for his family. Theseus was more than an electromechanical maze in which a mouse blunders around looking for the “cheese.” Built with his wife Betty, Shannon’s maze was an elegant display of telephone switching technology. When you make a telephone call, information travels the telephone system labyrinth to find the right telephone to ring, just as the mouse in this maze searches for its cheese.</item>
    	<item >\t The slide rule is the iconic instrument of the engineering profession. Every significant human-built structure of the past 150 years has involved its use. Invented at the time of the Mayflower, the “modern” slide rule (sometimes called the “Mannheim Rule”) dates to 1851, just a decade before MIT was founded. In the 19th century, the popularity of the slide rule grew along with the engineering profession, which needed a reliable means of quickly and accurately completing tedious but essential calculations. The ubiquitous engineer’s rule was the Log Log Duplex Decitrig. As described in Keuffel and Esser’s brochure, How to Choose a Slide Rule: “It has every scale you need for riding through a tough engineering course with a minimum of headaches. It will serve you well throughout the years to come when you graduate and take your place in the profession. For real knock-down-and-drag-out, math-eating, fire-breathing engineering, there isn’t another slide rule in the world that can touch it.”</item>
    	<item >\t Professor Vannevar Bush’s invention of the Differential Analyzer in 1931 “mechanized calculus.” This analog electromechanical device built with the assistance of Bush’s graduate students—Harold Hazen, Samuel Caldwell, Gordon Brown and Harold Edgerton—filled a room.. The integrator unit shown in detail here was one of six that were connected together by long metal rods and gears. Glass panels reveal the wheel-and-disc mechanism that performed the actual integration and helped provide the solution to complex differential equations. During the 1930s, Bush continued to develop this device, and many MIT laboratories benefited—including Harold Edgerton’s famous Strobe Lab and George Harrison’s Spectroscopy Lab. During World War II, the Differential Analyzer was used 24 hours a day, especially to help solve problems from the famous MIT Radiation Laboratory. Bush became a prominent figure when President Franklin D. Roosevelt named him to be his top science advisor during the war. After the war, Bush’s timely analysis, Science: The Endless Frontier, led to the creation of the National Science Foundation.</item>
    	<item >\t Even in an era of celebrity fascination, few architects are household names, but Frank Gehry probably comes closest to star status of anyone in his profession. MIT’s choice to hire Gehry to design the Ray and Maria Stata Center, a research and academic facility to replace the famous “Building 20,” represented a bold experiment in a new architectural language for the campus. The experience proved equal to MIT\'s engagement with architectural visionaries Alvar Aalto and Eero Saarinen in the decade after World War II. Further, the experiment has had a healthy mixed response at MIT, which for decades had established a conservative "corporate academic" approach to commissioning new architecture. It is difficult to be ambivalent about Gehry\'s vision or his extremely complex design of curved, inclined and projecting forms and enormous material variety. Yet, however one experiences this monumental structure (430,000 square feet), it energizes a dialogue about the meaning and function in architecture - a discussion that, some would argue, was largely absent at MIT for decades.</item>
    	<item >\t Sometimes described as “controlled lightning,” William Parker’s hand-blown glass plasma sculptures contain a mix of noble gases that are ionized by high-voltage, high-frequency signals. Parker “invented” the modern plasma globe in 1971 while conducting undergraduate physics research. Studying gaseous fuels for electrical rocket engines, he accidentally left a valve on, thereby filling his test chamber with neon and argon. The result was spectacular: streams of glowing colored light (just as you see here). Parker’s “invention” was actually a rediscovery of what Nikola Tesla learned almost a century earlier: electricity and plasma will produce light. It was after Parker first exhibited his plasma globe at the Exploratorium in San Francisco that plasma became popular. Maybe you have seen plasma globes on Star Trek, an amusement park, a Science Center, or even at home. Many artists at MIT have worked with plasma, most notably Alejandro Siña who created the “Glowing Needles” installation in the Alewife subway station of the MBTA Red Line.</item>
    	<item >\t Professor Stephen Benton’s interest in optical phenomena developed at an early age while he was watching the 3D film, The House of Wax. Benton invented white light transmission (or “rainbow”) holography at Polaroid in 1968. As a professor at MIT, Benton continued to explore the technology. In 1985, he created a 3D image of a green car floating in front of the Boston skyline that, unlike any previous hologram, was generated from a digital database. Benton thought this technique—synthetic, or digital, holography— would be very useful in medicine. That same year, Benton, members of his Spatial Imaging Group, and researchers from Brigham and Women’s Hospital collaborated to create this unique image of the human brain from MRI data. The coloring cues, partial transparency, and solid surfaces give this image context and add to its effectiveness. Throughout his life, Benton seamlessly blended art and technology. His creativity resulted in as many astonishing art pieces as breakthroughs in technology.</item>
    	<item >\t Glass is created by volcanoes, lightning, meteoric impacts, factory workers, artisans, and scientists. It is ancient and new, familiar and strange—and endlessly fascinating. (A Google search yields more than 370 million URLs for “glass”!) We look at it, through it, and with it.  Everyone knows it; no one fully understands it. The MIT Glass Lab combines all these dimensions as students, faculty, and artists collaborate on projects that engage their minds and hands in using and exploring this ubiquitous and mysterious material. A liquid as hard as rock, a solid that flows, a telescope lens, a building block, a windshield, an oboe, a pumpkin—no wonder the Glass Lab courses have the longest waiting lists of any at MIT.  The four objects here blend science, technology and art in fascinating ways and they represent their makers\' passions as well as those of MIT.</item>
    	<item >\t This popular public artwork can be found on the MIT main campus surrounding Building  6C on the first floor level.  On display here is is Lewitt’s linocut (20/75), Color Bands, 2000. (Gift of Vera G. List, List Visual Arts Center)
		\n \t An important work of art commands our attention, captivates us, stimulates reflection, and helps us see more than itself. Sol Lewitt’s work, here and elsewhere, has that expanding and lasting impact. His stunning mural in The Green (6C) is a provocative paradox. It is public art in a space the Boston Globe called “hidden away like a secret.” Some visitors come to MIT just to see it; others come across it unexpectedly and are astonished. We are taught that fine artworks are treasures to appreciate, not touch. Yet this is a floor; we walk on it. The space is neither locked nor guarded; it welcomes all. These elements – openness, startling discovery, mind-altering innovations in design and the use of materials – are the essence of MIT.</item>
    	<item >\t This iconic piece of public art can be found on the MIT campus in McDermott Court, near the tall Green Building (Building 54). Calder developed this monumental piece from models, including this one and another on display in the Wiesner Building.
		\n \t One of the most successful public art installations on campus is Calder\'s La Grand Voile (“Great Sail”) in McDermott Court, a monolithic stabile of black-painted steel.  This sculpture was an early acquisition for MIT\'s public art collection, which in 2006 was named one of the top ten such collections in the United States. Fabricated in France, Calder\'s 33-ton sculpture was disassembled, shipped to Cambridge and installed at MIT in 1966.  Its five intersecting, curved steel forms rise 40 feet, yet barely touch the ground, creating a playful tension between the massive structure and lightness of its footprint.  The sculptor trained as a mechanical engineer before pursuing a career in art, and his interest in giving expression to the dynamic interplay between art and engineering appealed to the MIT community.  In fact, Calder created the scale model pictured here for testing in MIT\'s Wright Brothers Wind Tunnel to determine the wind loads on the finished work.  During installation of the sculpture in 1966, Professors Harold Edgerton and Robert Shrock supervised the burial of a time capsule under it.  Contemporary reports stated that no date was set for digging up the capsule.</item>
    	<item >\t In 1970, burn victims who lost 60 to 90 percent of the skin on their bodies usually died from either fluid loss or bacterial infection. Too little skin was left to perform grafts, and substitutes had not yet worked. Materials Science Professor Ioannis Yannas was inspired by a meeting with Dr. John Burke of Harvard Medical School. Burke took Yannas to the Shriners Burn Hospital in Boston, making the urgency of the problem clear to him.  Yannas was the first to call attention to “the basic physics of the graft-wound interface.” Previous materials had been rejected by the patient, caused fatal blood clots or worse, and did not dissolve at the right rate, causing further agony. Yannas discovered a unique combination of the protein collagen—the strong fibrous material found in skin, bones and tendons, and carbohydrates known as “mucopolysaccharides”—which worked exceptionally well. By the mid 1970s, the first breakthrough was a membrane that allowed the dermis layer of skin to heal but still required further transplants. In 1982, Yannas and Burke announced they had developed a more advanced material that eliminated this second step. Although a major milestone, the work continues today at MIT—not only on skin, but also on all aspects of tissue and organ regeneration.</item>
    	<item >\t As a young man in 1953, H.M. suffered from crippling epilepsy that made it impossible to live independently. Convinced that removing part of H.M.’s brain would help, a surgeon cut out most of his hippocampus, the area with the most abnormal activity. H.M.’s epilepsy was mitigated, but tragically he lost his ability to form long-term memories. Professor Suzanne Corkin met H.M. in 1962 when she was a graduate student, and her study of him continues today. Corkin’s sensitive investigations, as well as those of nearly 100 other scientists, have taught us that specific parts of the brain are responsible for long-term memory, that profound memory impairment can leave overall intelligence intact, and that one can still learn a motor skill or other kinds of knowledge without being aware of that fact. H.M. died in 2008, but he is still contributing to science. Close scrutiny of the thin sections made from his brain will enable scientists to learn the exact location and extent of his lesion, which is the key to understanding the correlation between the brain and behavior. As Corkin observed in her eulogy for H.M.: “He has given the world a remarkable understanding of learning and memory.”</item>
    	<item >\t MIT Professor Hugh Herr lost both legs in 1982 when he was just 17 due to severe frostbite after getting caught in a blizzard while attempting a wintertime climb on Mount Washington. Within months of his surgeries, Herr started climbing again. He designed and built his own prosthetic legs and feet so he could climb on rocks or snow. As he experimented, Herr had a tremendous flash of inspiration: prosthetics could do more than mere replacement—he could make himself as tall or short as he liked. With good design, the injured individual could be better than before. This insight has proven just as revolutionary an idea as have many of his other prosthetic designs. Time magazine has twice named Herr’s prostheses to its top-ten inventions in the health field. His robotic ankle-foot was honored in 2007. The PowerFoot One shown here was manufactured by iWalk, a startup that Herr helped found, and is the first to allow an amputee to walk with a normal gait.</item>
    	<item >\t MIT Professor Norbert Wiener broke his hip in 1962. During his recovery, he shared his speculations that servomechanisms could be used to link the brain to an artificial limb. The Massachusetts General Hospital doctors were intrigued. Shortly thereafter, MIT Mechanical Engineering Professor Robert Mann was recruited to provide advice on the design of a small, lightweight power system similar to the ones he had developed for the Sparrow missile. Soon Mann was completely engaged with orthopedic surgeon Melvin Glimcher. In 1968, they demonstrated the “Boston Arm,” the first artificial limb that used electrical signals from the brain to control its movement. It took engineers at Liberty Mutual Insurance Company many more years of development to create a viable prosthesis. This display shows one of the earliest experiments and two working prototypes, one developed for Liberty Mutual. The research on the control systems for artificial arms by Stephen Jacobsen, Robert Mann’s doctoral student, would become the basis for the development of an equally famous prosthesis, the Utah Arm.</item>
    	<item >\t “What magical trick makes us intelligent? The trick is that there is no trick. The power of intelligence stems from our vast diversity, not from any single, perfect principle.” – Marvin Minsky, The Society of Mind
		\n \t In the late 1960s and early 1970s, Professor Marvin Minsky created a robotic arm that used a video camera and computer to build with children’s blocks. This work was the principal inspiration and source of ideas for his landmark book on the workings of the human mind, The Society of Mind (1986). While it might seem counterintuitive to build a machine without a conceptual framework, the method proved surprisingly effective and gave rise to Minsky’s theory that the mind is composed of a multitude of little processes called “agents.” As Minsky put it: “Each mental agent by itself can only do some simple thing that needs no mind or thought at all. Yet when we join these agents in societies—in certain very special ways—this leads to true intelligence.”</item>
    	<item >\t Ernesto Blanco has been waiting five decades for someone to build a full-scale working version of his self-propelled stair-climbing and descending wheelchair. In 1959, the National Inventors Council offered a $5,000 prize for the design of a wheelchair that could climb stairs. Blanco submitted his design in 1962. The Council never awarded the prize, but Blanco was so convinced his design would work that he built this one-quarter  scale model to prove the concept. How? The secret is the angles and the fact that “static reactions are always vertical and have no tendency to slip,” explains Blanco.
		\n \t Blanco not only brought this “inventional wisdom” to his MIT students, but also conveyed a deeply held belief that solving a problem such as a stair-climbing wheel was a form of social justice and, therefore, progress. About a decade ago, Dean Kamen introduced the iBot, a fantastic motorized wheelchair, but production stopped in 2009 because neither insurance nor Medicare would pay for it. Blanco sees that as a challenge and the reason he still wants someone to build his chair.</item>
    	<item >\t Since the damming of the Charles River in the 1800s, nothing has reshaped the face of Boston more profoundly than the Central Artery/Tunnel Project, also known as the “Big Dig". The megaproject buried the aging Central Artery elevated highway, reconnected the city with its waterfront, opened a third harbor tunnel, cut back pollution, and gave Boston a new landmark—the Leonard Zakim Bunker Hill Memorial Bridge. The biggest highway construction project in the United States, the $15 billion-plus Big Dig not only sped traffic flow on what had been the country’s most overloaded roads, but also fit within a grand scheme to minimize Boston’s dependence on the automobile and maximize public transportation. The effort was shepherded patiently for many years by Frederick Salvucci, ’61, SM ’62, longtime Commonwealth Secretary of Transportation, transportation system expert, and now MIT senior lecturer.</item>
    	<item >\t MIT architects and urban planners have shaped many features of Boston. The most recent compelling effort is the Boston Chinatown Master Plan released in the spring of 2010 following a two-year process led by the Chinatown Gateway Coalition. The stated goal of the coalition was to create a community vision for the 20-acre Chinatown Gateway/South Bay Special Study Area and update the Chinatown Master Plan. One of the plan’s guiding figures is MIT Urban Studies Professor Tunney Lee. Few planners have loved or contributed more to our understanding of Boston’s many neighborhoods than Lee, the former chief of planning and design at the Boston Redevelopment Authority. Chinatown is special for Lee, however, since he has lived in this neighborhood for nearly 70 years. Lee’s first MIT graduate student, Randall Imai, drew the Community Plan on display here, and other MIT alumni have been involved in this latest effort to enhance and preserve one of the nation’s oldest and most important Chinatown neighborhoods.</item>
    	<item >\t From 1954 to 1960, Professors Kevin Lynch and Gyorgy Kepes led “Perceptual Form of the City,” a research project studying human perceptions of the urban landscape and how those perceptions should influence city planning. As part of the study, MIT students were asked to draw maps of the City of Boston. The maps on exhibit collate data from individual students’ maps and show how frequently certain features of the city appeared.
		\n \t In addition to their work with students, MIT researchers for “Perceptual Form of the City” went into Boston to investigate citizens’ mental maps, asking passersby questions such as, “How do I get to the Public Garden?” This research helped Lynch form his early theories of city planning, published in 1960 by the MIT Press in The Image of the City. Considered at the time of its publication to be the most important work in the field for over 150 years, The Image of the City is a classic in planning literature and an exposition of Lynch’s views of what the form of a city can mean to its citizens.</item>
    	<item >\t The Charles River not only is intimately connected with MIT’s identity, but also has served as a laboratory for the Institute. Faculty and students make constant use of the Charles, perhaps none more so than Harold Edgerton. Famous for his high-speed photographs, Edgerton made equally important contributions to underwater exploration, including the development of side scan sonar technology. In the early 1950s, Edgerton began experimenting with sonar to focus deep-sea photographs. In 1961, when his student Martin Klein (SB ’62) was seeking a senior thesis topic, Edgerton suggested signal processing of his sonar data. The project was so successful that he hired Klein to lead the sonar systems program. Klein led the development of the Mark I, the first commercially successful dual-channel side scan sonar. In 1967, Klein left to form his own company, Klein Associates, Inc., and continued the tradition of testing his equipment in the Charles. On display is the company’s first side scan sonar, the MK-300 (1970).</item>
    	<item >\t When windows suddenly crack and fall out of a high-rise building, the results are heart stopping. This happened to MIT’s Green Building (1960s) and the famous John Hancock Tower in Boston (1973). The Green Building had another significant problem: Whenever it was windy, it was nearly impossible for pedestrians to enter or exit the building. The MIT AeroAstro Department’s extensive wind tunnel investigations of the Green Building were crucial to the subsequent analysis of similar problems on the other side of the Charles River.
		\n \t Director of MIT\'s Wright Brothers Wind Tunnel Frank Durgin was the key figure in most of this work.  His most significant contribution came in the 1980s when the Boston Redevelopment Authority (BRA) commissioned MIT to prepare guidelines for the assessment of the effect on pedestrian-level winds by a new large structure. Durgin had led numerous studies of Boston building projects, including this 1979 model for a new building at One Post Office Square. His proposal provided a means for the BRA to standardize results and ensure that its legal requirements were being met.
		\n \t Frank Durgin\'s tests of a 1/600 scale model of the John Hancock Tower and Boston\'s Back Bay were one part of a larger study led by Civil Engineering Professor Robert Hansen.</item>
    	<item >\t MIT’s pioneering role in weather radar began at the Radiation Laboratory during WWII. Following the war, the military transferred several radar systems to MIT, which quickly became a key center for weather radar research. For his study of hailstorms, Professor Spiros “Speed” Geotis instigated one of the earliest “citizen science” research programs. Geotis teamed up with WBZ-TV meteorologists Don Kent, Bob Copeland, and Norm MacDonald, who in turn invited residents in metropolitan Boston to send in a postcard any time they experienced a hailstorm. The key data included: address, date and time of the storm, and the size of the hailstones. Postcards poured into WBZ. Geotis compared this information to the data obtained from MIT’s radar equipment. (The klystron displayed in the MIT 150 Exhibition is the device that produced the radar waves.) Not only did Geotis prove one could use radar to predict the location of hailstorms, but the quantity and detail of citizen data also showed that it was possible to estimate the size of the hailstones.</item>
    	<item >\t When President Charles Vest unveiled MIT OpenCourseWare (OCW) in 2001, the outside reaction was surprise: MIT would give away all its course materials online? But the novel idea built directly on core values: the Institute would continue to focus its own teaching on face-to-face instruction, while acting as a leader in providing accessible learning resources worldwide for non-commercial use and modification at no charge. Launched in 2002, the OCW website was an immediate global hit. Today, virtually all MIT courses may be found on OCW, many of them translated into multiple languages. More than 125 million people have visited the website. One of the biggest hits has been Professor Walter Lewin’s engaging Newtonian mathematics videos, which at one point were number one on YouTube. In a favorite class episode, Professor Lewin illustrated energy conservation by, among other tricks, riding this pendulum ball.</item>
    	<item >\t In addition to the typical class lectures, MIT campus organizations sponsor several lecture series that bring noted speakers to campus. One of the most prestigious, the Compton Lecture Series, named for MIT President Karl Taylor Compton, originally brought one lecturer to campus for a residency of at least a week, giving three lectures on a general subject for the entire campus community and several more specialized seminars.  Today the Institute invites one or two distinguished scientists, politicians, activists, and artists from around the world to present a single lecture on a topic of significance.  Over the past 50 years, the major theme has been the role of science and technology in society.  Paul A. Samuelson, an Institute Professor and the first American to win the Nobel Prize in economics, gave the 1969 lecture as a conversation with Milton Friedman, debating old and new systems of economics and monetary policy.</item>
    	<item >\t In the early days of Boston public broadcasting, MIT was a main supporter of WGBH, whose Channel 2 television effort began in space rented from the Institute near the current Stratton Student Center. MIT and WGBH jointly produced MIT Science Reporter, a pioneering effort to ask scientists and engineers to explain their work to a general audience on television. The program, hosted by deep-voiced MIT science reporter John Fitch (’52), offered lengthy but easily understood interviews that represented a broad range of subjects.  Shot with very few takes, the programs required intensive planning. Candid correspondence between WGBH and MIT indicates that some of the “talent” (aka the faculty) were more adept than others at giving a good interview. The goal was to increase public understanding of science and technology not only through broadcasts of the program, but also through a special lending library that made 16mm film copies available to schools and libraries across the nation.</item>
    	<item >\t When physicist Max Born visited in 1926, the Institute published his lectures under its own imprint. That exercise initiated MIT book publishing efforts that accelerated in 1962 with the formation of the MIT Press, an independent publishing house focusing strongly, but not exclusively, on science and technology. The MIT Press has published more than 9,000 titles, known both for their breadth and depth of intellectual coverage and for their striking design and production. Many of the MIT Press’s books have become the defining texts in their fields. In some cases, such as Michael Gazzaniga’s classic reference, The Cognitive Neurosciences, they have been instrumental in moving the discipline forward. Tucked inside a custom bookcase that captures Muriel Cooper’s famous colophon is a collection of 30 influential works that remind us that the MIT Press has provided a key platform for shaping entire disciplines and discourses far beyond the campus.</item>
    	<item >\t From the time of its founding in 1861, delegates from MIT attended many of the major expositions and world’s fairs. In 1893 and 1904, the Institute contributed exhibitions that showcased its educational achievements. Beginning with the 1893 World’s Columbian Exposition held in Chicago, MIT prepared an extensive collection of portfolios filled with hundreds of images. In 1904, MIT updated these volumes for the Louisiana Purchase Exposition in St. Louis. For over a decade, more than 1,000 photographs depicting every aspect of the campus, equipment, and student life were compiled in large, red-bound volumes for prospective students and other interested visitors to peruse. One alumnus who visited the display described the Columbian Exposition this way: “The collection as a whole represented the Institute so well, that it is said if the entire institution were to be swept away, it could be reconstructed from the information contained in the exhibit.”</item>
    	<item >\t More than 13,000 people waited in the Boston Garden to hear Winston Churchill on March 31, 1949. The former and future British prime minister did not disappoint. In a keynote for MIT’s Mid-Century Convocation, Churchill gave an Olympian and well-received speech that swept across 50 years of global history into a tough but measured analysis of the Cold War, which was delivered during the Berlin Airlift. The address was seen as his most important since the Iron Curtain speech three years earlier. Wryly admitting that “I have no technical and no university education, and have just had to pick up a few things as I went along,” Churchill took an optimistic view of science’s potential to tackle key problems such as hunger. After two days of related and highly public presentations on science, technology, society, and governmental policy, the Convocation ended with the inauguration of MIT President James R. Killian.</item>
    	<item >\t Every year at MIT, each successive graduating class produces more entrepreneurs who start their first companies sooner. No less than 12 percent of those graduating from the MIT Sloan School of Management in 2010 already were forming companies. The most public face of the Institute’s entrepreneurial culture is the $100K Entrepreneurship Competition that include 3 unique contests.  The most famous, the Business Plan Competition, is a student-run yearlong educational experience that encourages students and researchers to commercialize their ideas and talents.  The winner of the Business Plan Contest receives a $100,000 prize. Started in 1989 as the $10K Competition, the event has helped to launch more than 130 companies that have generated over 2,500 jobs and received $770 million in venture capital funding. The 2010 top prizewinner, C-Crete Technologies, aims to change radically how the world makes cement.</item>
    	<item >\t “To create educational opportunities for the world’s poorest children by providing each child with a rugged, low-cost, low-power, connected laptop with content and software designed for collaborative, joyful, self-empowered learning.” That’s the vision of the One Laptop per Child (OLPC) project, kicked off in a 2005 Davos presentation by Professor Nicholas Negroponte, with the goal of providing a complete laptop for $100. Faced with skepticism about computer purchases among groups that are often short on basic learning supplies, and competing with aggressively priced models from conventional suppliers, the project has grappled with difficulties in boosting production volumes and dropping prices. (This model debuted in 2007 at a respectable $188.) Although OLPC struggles to keep its doors open, more than one million of its elegant designs are in the hands of children across the globe.</item>
    	<item >\t “...the Committee does not feel that the commercial use is likely to be of major importance.” – MIT Patent Committee
		\n \t Professor Arthur Ruge felt differently about his strain gauge. Ruge invented the device in 1938 to help his graduate student John Meier complete his investigation of earthquake stress on elevated water tanks. It was simple: a tiny piece of high-resistance filament was bent in a zigzag pattern and fixed in a rigid base (glue). The gauge was applied to the surface he wanted to test. Any stress on the surface could be easily detected by measuring the changes in electrical resistance of the current running through the wires of the gauge. Having been granted full rights to his invention, Ruge began the patent application process. Discovering that E.E. Simmons of Caltech had invented the same device a year earlier, the two men together applied for the patent. In 1939, Ruge started a business with MIT Professor Alfred deForest to manufacture the SR-4 gauge (the initials S and R honor the inventors), a device used in virtually all commercial weighing scales, in every structural stress test—and it even allowed astronaut Neil Armstrong to declare: “The Eagle has landed.”</item>
    	<item >\t In 1930, Alfred P. Sloan, Jr., was worried that his engineers at General Motors knew nothing about management. A year later, a new yearlong “Sponsored Fellowships Program” for mid-career management stars from companies and organizations around the world debuted. With sponsorship from Sloan, the program known as the MIT Sloan Fellowship Program for Executive Development began in 1938.
		\n \t Vice Admiral (ret.) Vivien Crea, USCG, arrived at MIT in 1991. She was already a star in the military: one of the first two women aviators in the Coast Guard and the first female military presidential aide. There are many distinguished Sloan Fellows, but Crea is the only one to have carried the nuclear football. Military Challenge Coins such as these are presented during certain milestone ceremonies in an individual’s career. Although she did not receive a coin, for Crea, completion of her Sloan Fellowship year was an especially important milestone vital to the success of her career.</item>
    	<item >\t “MIT” is internationally recognized shorthand for technological and academic excellence. When filmmakers want to establish a character as a brilliant scientist or engineer, they throw in a line about her MIT education or cut to his class ring. So when advertisements in the 1930s showed a serious white-coated MIT scientist holding aloft a flask with “the perfect cup of coffee,” the American public listened. In 1920, the National Coffee Roasters Association gave Professor Samuel Cate Prescott $40,000 to establish a new laboratory devoted to perfecting coffee. The resulting guidelines—one tablespoon of coffee per eight ounces of water, just short of boiling, in glass or ceramic containers, never boiled, reheated, or reused—were the result of three years of study. More important than the recipe, however, was the refutation of coffee opponents who claimed coffee was a “slow poison.” Wrote Prescott, “Coffee was the servant rather than the destroyer of civilization.” MIT researchers also were active in serious food technologies, working on techniques for preserving taste, nutrition, and texture in canned goods as well as developing nutritional guidelines for preventing nutritional deficiencies.</item>
    	<item >\t In an unusually candid letter to MIT President Karl Compton, an official from Lee Laboratories related that many in industry were upset to learn that MIT was creating an official patent policy. Many companies were bringing work to MIT because it lacked such a policy. In the depths of the Great Depression and desperate for income, the fact that the Institute could profit from its inventions was of considerable interest to the MIT administration. Professor Vannevar Bush led the effort to draft a patent policy in 1931 that was subsequently approved by the faculty in 1932. The policy made clear what inventions and discoveries would be considered property of MIT and how the Institute would determine if it wished to retain or return those rights. Today, the Technology Licensing Office goes many steps further to facilitate specific industry-Institute partnerships and to develop appropriate licensing arrangements.</item>
    	<item >\t Sequencing the 3 billion DNA letters in the human genome was a scientific and technological accomplishment as ambitious as the Moon landing—and the achievement immediately brought profound and practical results in biological and medical research. When the International Human Genome Sequencing Consortium published the public version of the genome in 2003, it was the culmination of an extraordinary 13-year race in which scientific advances and engineering developments ran hand-in-hand. Under the leadership of mathematician-turned-biologist Eric Lander, the Whitehead/MIT Center for Genome Research at the Whitehead Institute for Biomedical Research (an MIT affiliate) was the largest contributor of data.
		\n \t When you hear the phrase “mapping the human genome,” that describes work by Thomas Hudson who first came to the Whitehead in 1991 and joined Lander’s project soon thereafter. Among his key contributions was the first physical map of the genome. Two mementos on display celebrate that achievement: a laminated commemorative print of the Chromosome 14 map and a framed issue of Science in which the map was first announced.</item>
    	<item >\t Like a many-faceted Fresnel lens shining light wherever it turns, Harold E. (Doc) Edgerton illuminated every corner of MIT and the world. Explorer, teacher, artist, storyteller, entrepreneur, mentor, inventor, and more, he showed us unseen worlds beneath the seas, in the skies, and in the world around us. He created fields, industries, and new ways of seeing and imagining. By enhancing our power to perceive, he created new paths to understanding and to beneficial practical results. For him, science, engineering, problem solving, art, and human values were all an interconnected web, not separate domains. His flashes of light were equaled by his flashes of insight, and he has given us a more effective and more beautiful world. Gentle and modest, he did not seek the spotlight. He simply did his work, shared his passions, and caused the world to sparkle and glow.</item>
    	<item >\t The largest air-insulated Van de Graaff generator in the world was built by Robert van de Graaff in 1931. He was recruited to come to MIT in 1930 when his Princeton colleague Karl Compton became the Institute’s president. The dramatic black-and-white photo by Berenice Abbott on display at the MIT Museum was taken at the machine’s first location, an unused dirigible hangar at the Round Hill Estate in Dartmouth, MA. Later the 40-foot-high machine was moved to the MIT campus on a series of trucks and train cars. As an active piece of research equipment at MIT, the generator was used to produce high voltages for experiments in nuclear medicine and radiography, and to power MIT’s particle accelerator. The machine is still in use today—on permanent display at Boston’s Museum of Science—where it is the star of daily lightning shows.</item>
    	<item >\t The Atomic Bomb changed everything in the post-WWII world of physics education. Faculty and students studied quantum theory and the theory of relativity, grappling with the fundamental laws governing matter and energy. Federal dollars for research poured into the Physics department to support this work. Every university faced the same problem: How to educate the next generation of physicists? MIT decided to maintain a diverse research agenda balancing nuclear and non-nuclear research programs. With generous funding, physicists also developed new research tools such as accelerators and bubble chambers to conduct extremely complex experiments. They soon found themselves struggling with an immense amount of data. One significant development was the Feynman Diagram, a pictorial device that represented the interactions of elementary particles. Developed by Richard Feynman (MIT ’39) in 1949, popularized by Freeman Dyson, physics graduate students quickly adopted the ingenious tool that showed a researcher how to calculate the behavior of those particles.</item>
    	<item >\t Well known for both his groundbreaking contributions to linguistics and philosophy as well as his political activism, Noam Chomsky has taught at MIT for over 55 years. When Chomsky joined the department in the 1950s, linguistics at MIT was classified as a “communication science,” affiliated with the Research Laboratory of Electronics. The department’s physical location in Building 20 encouraged formal and informal collaboration with individuals and groups working on cybernetics, acoustics, and artificial intelligence. This manuscript from 1955 is one of Chomsky’s first works on his influential concept of generative grammar: the idea that humans have some innate knowledge of grammar from birth, and that language acquisition cannot totally be explained by the relatively sparse stimuli they are exposed to as pre-verbal children.</item>
    	<item >\t MIT built its first wind tunnel in 1913 in the first building on what would become MIT’s Cambridge campus in 1916. It was the first university in the United States to offer a graduate degree in aeronautical engineering in 1914. When MIT hired Jerome Hunsaker in 1913 to teach aeronautical engineering, the first thing Hunsaker did was visit all the laboratories and wind tunnels in Europe. Thanks to MIT President Richard Maclaurin’s previous association with the National Physical Laboratory in England, Hunsaker secured copies of a plan for a basic atmospheric wind tunnel. Hunsaker’s assistant Edward Warner and student Donald Douglas built the wind tunnel and installed the Cambridge Scientific balance on display. Soon thereafter, Warner became chief scientist for the fledgling National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics (NACA). First thing he did? Build the NACA’s first wind tunnel based on the MIT/NPL design. Donald Douglas left MIT to found Douglas Aircraft Company. For nearly a century, the department has produced numerous pioneers in the field.</item>
    	<item >\t “We don’t have a utopian vision. We have a set of ideas that we think are important to discuss. Those ideas largely have to do with sustainability of cities. The ability of cities to, over time, remain in balance with the resource streams that are available to them... .”  – William J. Mitchell
		\n \t The Smart Cities Group at the MIT Media Laboratory puts its ideas into action.  This is a prototype of the CityCar, a lightweight, intelligent, electric vehicle, that the Group believes will one day radically reduce the energy consumption and carbon footprints of cities. The key enabling technology is a “robot wheel” that integrates drive, steering, suspension, and braking inside each wheel. This not only simplifies the design of the chassis and body, but also enables extraordinary mobility. The CityCar is also capable of folding to minimize its urban footprint. A traditional parking space can fit up to three CityCars. Each CityCar can rapidly recharge within 15 minutes at electric charging stations distributed in an urban area. They are most effectively used to form intelligently coordinated, citywide, one-way, shared-use programs, otherwise known as “mobility-on-demand” systems.</item>
    	<item >\t “Seventy percent of what I’m now doing I couldn’t have foreseen five years ago. You take unexpected twists and turns.” – Susan Lindquist
		\n \t Within each of your cells, each one of the millions of proteins intricately folds into a proper shape to do its precise job.  If it misfolds, that leads to problems that play a role in cancer, neurodegenerative diseases, and other ailments. Professor Susan Lindquist has uncovered surprising roles, both positive and negative, for protein misfolding in disease and evolution. Lindquist’s work focuses most closely on a special group of proteins called “heat shock proteins” that have the specific job of helping other proteins fold and mature correctly. That generalized understanding has permitted still more focused research on the treatment of disease. Lindquist has won many awards, including most recently the National Medal of Science in 2010.</item>
    	<item >\t Salvador Luria won the 1969 Nobel Prize in Physiology and Medicine with Max Delbrück and Alfred Hershey for the study of bacteriophages. He received many letters of congratulations, including a few from friends who thought he had won the Peace Prize because at that time Luria was as well known for his anti-Vietnam activism as for his biology. Two years later, after Congress passed the National Cancer Act of 1971, Luria immediately applied for funds to build a new cancer research facility at MIT. Here was a way he could combine biology and social justice. When the MIT Center for Cancer Research (now the David H. Koch Institute for Integrative Cancer Research at MIT) opened in 1974, Luria had assembled an exceptional team. One of those recruits was Phillip Sharp who recalled: “Salva was a visionary who protected his young faculty from unnecessary interruptions, thus allowing their research programs to flourish in an ideal scientific environment. He was also a role model for how a scientist could shape and lead a community.”</item>
    	<item >\t The beginning of nuclear science and engineering research at MIT dates back to World War II and involves numerous departments. After the war, MIT recruited faculty who had been involved in atomic energy projects in order to foster education and research in the field. In 1951, Manson Benedict, a key member of the Manhattan Project, was hired to become MIT’s first professor of nuclear engineering. In 1958, MIT created a new Department of Nuclear Science and Engineering led by Benedict through 1971.
		\n \tThe MIT Nuclear Reactor Laboratory is an interdepartmental research center that operates a 5 MW reactor in support of MIT’s educational and research missions. The reactor began 24/7 research and teaching service to MIT in July of 1958. MITR–II is equipped with many experimental facilities. Service to the outside community includes research in nuclear medicine, environmental trace element analysis, operational safety for commercial reactors, and neutron transmutation doping of silicon for high-energy applications.</item>
    	<item >\t Originally developed in 2009 by the MIT SENSEable City Laboratory, the now commercially available Copenhagen Wheel on display is a device for sustainable mobility that offers a cost-effective transportation alternative to the automobile. The device transforms existing bicycles into hybrids with regeneration and real-time sensing capabilities. Its sleek red hub contains a battery-powered motor and an internal gear system—helping cyclists overcome hilly terrain and long distances—and environmental and location sensors that provide data for cycling-related mobile applications. Cyclists can use this data to plan bike routes, to achieve their exercise goals, or to create connections with other cyclists. Through sharing their data with friends or their city, they also are contributing to a larger pool of information from which the whole community can benefit.</item>
    	<item >\t MIT presidents, faculty, and alumni have served in many important roles aiding governments around the world, but particularly significant is the role many have played as U.S. presidential science advisors. Vannevar Bush, advisor to Franklin Roosevelt during World War II, was the first; MIT alumnus John Holdren, advisor to Barack Obama is the most recent. Dwight Eisenhower turned to MIT President James R. Killian at a particularly tense time following the Soviet Union’s successful launch of Sputnik in 1957. Killian had given serious thought to the role of science advice at the highest levels of government for many years. In 1955, he spoke of it in a special lecture series on national security policy at Harvard. As Eisenhower’s Special Assistant to the President for Science and Technology, he had the opportunity to put his ideas into action. Killian oversaw the creation of the President’s Science Advisory Committee, the new National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), the nation’s missile programs, and a limited nuclear test ban treaty.</item>
    	<item >\t MIT is a hard place. It is hard because of unrelenting pressure to master difficult materials quickly. It is hard because the time to do all that is required is inadequate. It is also hard if you are black or Hispanic or female or gay/lesbian or transgendered or blind or religious or from a culture hostile to the United States or in any way different from whatever norms are perceived to exist in the larger society.
		\n \t “Tech is Hell” is how older generations of students put it. “IHTFP,” which stands for many things, is how today’s students express a complicated relationship with a community they both love and hate. MIT President Jerome Wiesner believed the point was not to deny such experiences, but to transcend them: “I hope that your MIT education has given you the objectivity and breadth to help yourself, your social group, your profession, your region, your country, and the world to bridge the many intellectual and emotional gaps that make understanding difficult.” Whether striving to improve MIT or change the world, reconciling IHTFP may be the Institute’s most important moral lesson of all time.</item>
    	<item >\t When MIT was founded in 1861, most students lived locally and commuted from home. As the Institute’s reputation and enrollment increased, however, more students from outside Massachusetts matriculated, thus heightening the demand for housing. Sigma Chi, the Institute’s first fraternity, was founded in 1882, and many more fraternities followed in the coming decade. The role played by fraternities and later sororities and other independent living groups would prove critical in the 20th century. Not only do the FSILGs (Fraternities, Sororities, and Independent Living Groups) house a significant percentage of all students, but they also demonstrate the value of small, cohesive, and supportive living groups to the MIT undergraduate experience. Not all of MIT’s Greeks provide housing. Alpha Kappa Alpha, MIT’s first sorority chartered in 1977, for example, was inspired by MIT Dean Mary Hope. She believed that black women on campus would benefit from the strong support network provided by this national service and learning sorority.</item>
    	<item >\t What happens if you take a full-sized piano and drop it from the top of a six-story building? In 1972, Baker House dormitory residents decided to find out. They hauled a piano to the roof of Alvar Aalto’s sinuous red brick architectural masterpiece and heaved it onto Amherst Alley. The stunt has been repeated several times since, and students consider it a much-beloved tradition. In recent years, the Piano Drop event has moved to the riverside of the dorm and takes place at 5 p.m. on the last day in the spring term when students may drop a class. Though this event is widely popular among the MIT community, it is controversial, as some object to the destruction of a musical instrument. One participant responded, “The Baker House Piano Drop is actually a combination of dorm spirit, harmless destructiveness, and the willingness to do something difficult just for the sake of doing it.” Shown here are the final results of the 2010 enactment, or rather those that the MIT Museum staff could scrape from the lawn below.</item>
    	<item >\t Practical jokes are part of undergraduate life almost everywhere. But nowhere else do they rival MIT’s tradition in sophistication or integration into the intellectual culture of the campus. Called “hacks,” they follow a code of ethics—no one harmed physically or emotionally, and nothing damaged. Often taking years of planning and teams from many disciplines, they become the stuff of legend, infusing our community with humor even as we marvel at the creativity, talent, and tenacity they display. Partisans dispute their relative majesty much like sports fans arguing about teams from decades past. They attract national attention to the imagination and technical proficiency that MIT fosters. Oliver Smoot, a freshman in 1958, became a unit of measurement—placed on the Harvard Bridge and moved 364 times as Smoot marks were painted (364.4, +/- one ear). Rebuilding the bridge in 1987 included renewing the marks. Today, the Smoot is a widely known metric, even as an option in Google Earth! “Best ever,” Smoot fans affirm. A police car on the dome, MIT’s triumph at the Harvard-Yale game, Cal Tech’s cannon suddenly appearing, Greenspeak—these also have devout advocates. Together, they proclaim that the spirit of MIT sizzles with clever prowess.</item>
    	<item >\t Alumni around the world recognize each other by their brass rats—a distinctive class ring featuring the Institute’s mascot, the beaver. Suggested by students and alumni, the beaver was chosen as the mascot this way:
		\n \t “We first thought of the kangaroo, which, like Tech, goes forward by leaps and bounds. Then we considered the elephant. He is wise, patient, strong, hard working, and—like all those who graduate from Tech—has a good tough hide. But neither of these were American animals. We turned to [William Temple] Hornaday’s book on the animals of North America and instantly chose the beaver. The beaver not only typifies the Tech [student], but his habits are peculiarly our own as well. The beaver is noted for his engineering, mechanical skills, and industry. His habits are nocturnal. He does his best work in the dark.”</item>
    	<item >\t MIT’s formative years in Boston yielded a distinct and bold vision for scientific and technological education at the start of the 20th century. Richard Cockburn Maclaurin, a new, young president, set forth a plan and challenged the Institute’s alumni to build a “New Tech”—a massive and majestic campus on the banks of the Charles River that would serve the needs of the Institute and declare the centrality of research in the modern world. The endeavor to design such a facility proved challenging, but the result was an exceptional synthesis of architectural and engineering ideals. William Welles Bosworth, an architect and MIT alumnus, embraced many of the concepts that originated from architects and engineers during earlier planning phases, but in a wholly original manner. It is easy to see the surface symbols: a great dome—inspired by Thomas Jefferson’s adaptation at the University of Virginia of the ancient Roman Pantheon symbolizes the universality of all knowledge—and a classical portico of immense solidity is a homage to Bosworth’s own training and MIT’s vital role in introducing Beaux Arts principles of architectural instruction to the United States. Of equal significance in the design is a structure of steel and concrete that follows the latest developments in building engineering, which gave a spatial flexibility to the interior plan that was essential to a growing institution. The arrangement of the interior teaching, research, and administrative spaces reflects the diverse influences of scientific management and modern factory design. Scientific buildings are usually temporal structures, yielding to the ever-changing imperatives of new research. Therefore, the endurance of MIT’s Main Group is all the more remarkable as a testament to excellence in design and to the founder’s original vision.</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>